spikesource.com 2009-03-02

# Privacy Policy | SpikeSource

## Purpose and Scope

This policy discloses what information we gather about you when you visit SpikeSource domains, use SpikeSource tools, or buy products directly from us. It describes how we use that information and how you can control it. 

## Information SpikeSource, Inc. Gathers and Tracks

SpikeSource, Inc. collects two kinds of information about users: 1) data that users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, subscribing to mailing lists or email delivery of our information systems, completing surveys, submitting information from our desktop tools or buying directly from us; and 2) aggregated tracking data we may collect when users interact with our Website or service interfaces. 

## Personal Information

We use the personal information you provide voluntarily to send information you have requested and to fulfill requests, for site and tool personalization and for statistical purposes. The specific use of your personal information varies, depending on how you contact us: 

  * When you subscribe to SpikeSource mailing lists to receive SpikeSource news and product information, you must provide an email address. We use that email address to send the requested information. We never sell or rent your email address that you provide when subscribing to our lists. 

  * When you post information to SpikeSource public mailing lists or message bases, this information will be visible to the public. Moreover, SpikeSource mailing lists may be archived by third-party sites over which SpikeSource, Inc. has no control, and your email address can be found from their archives. 

  * When you choose to share information with us, for example through our desktop tools or Website, we may report on that submission in anonymous statistical form, as well as use that information for site or content personalization. 

  * When you order SpikeSource products, subscribe to our services, or request information from us that depends upon your technology use, we record the technologies you're using in order to provide the service. Where that service may in part be provided through a partner, we will share your information with the partner in anonymous form. Our partner relationships provide equivalent privacy protection for such information as provided by this policy itself. We may also add you to our mailing lists and will contact you with SpikeSource-related issues now and then. 

  * We may from time to time offer certain programs with limited participation, for example closed beta programs. When you participate in such programs, we may require additional information to permit selection of participants. In addition, we will contact participants to collect program feedback periodically. These communications are not promotional in nature. 

  * Where we may use third parties in fulfilling some of our services, we share only the information necessary to fulfill the service, and our partner agreements provide equivalent privacy protection for such information as provided by this policy itself. 

We only release identifiable personal information when we believe that release is appropriate to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property or safety of SpikeSource, Inc., our users or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

## Aggregated Tracking Information

We may analyze visitors' use of our sites and tools by tracking information such as downloads, page views, traffic flow, search terms and click-through. We use this information to improve our products and sites. We may also share or publish this anonymous traffic and demographic information in aggregate form. We do not share or publish any information that can identify an individual user. 

## Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

## Cookies and Advertising

A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser when you visit our sites. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your computer, so that we can provide you with personalized information and features. We may use cookies to help track user traffic patterns. This information is not linked to personally identifiable information. We use this anonymous data to improve our products and sites. 

We may use an outside advertising company to display advertisements on our site. These advertisements may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Website, cookies received with banner or other ads are collected by these advertising companies, and we do not have access to or control over this information. 

You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies or to block cookies. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features or functions. 

## Links

This site may contain links to other sites. SpikeSource, Inc. is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Websites. 

## Surveys

We may run surveys on our site in which we ask our users for contact information (such as their email address). We may, with permission, use the contact information from the entry form to ask follow-up questions. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings. (See the choice and opt-out section below.) 

## Security

This site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All the data regarding users, their computers' system information and benchmark results are stored on a server. This server is located in a locked and guarded space, and only authorized SpikeSource, Inc. personnel have access to the database containing given usernames and passwords. 

## Notification of Changes

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on www.spikesource.com. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by email. Users will be able to opt out of any new use of their personal information. 

## Choice and Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us and from our partners at the point where we request information about the user. 

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database, so that they no longer receive future communications or access to our other services: 

  * You can unsubscribe from any of our mailing lists through your login profile at _<http://www.spikesource.com/sitemgr/site-login.php>_. 

  * You can unsubscribe from any email subscription to blogs, message bases, bug tracking systems and so forth through your access to that system. 

  * You can send email to _[info@spikesource.com](mailto:%69%6E%66%6F%40%73%70%69%6B%65%73%6F%75%72%63%65%2E%63%6F%6D)_ stating your request. 

  * You can reply to any unwanted communications that you receive, stating your request. 

## Contacting the Website

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Website, you can contact _[webmaster@spikesource.com](mailto:%77%65%62%6D%61%73%74%65%72%40%73%70%69%6B%65%73%6F%75%72%63%65%2E%63%6F%6D)_ and/or _[privacy@spikesource.com](mailto:%70%72%69%76%61%63%79%40%73%70%69%6B%65%73%6F%75%72%63%65%2E%63%6F%6D)_. 

Version 2.1, November 2005

## Purpose and Scope

We encourage you to read this policy to ensure you understand SpikeSource’s privacy practices. This policy outlines our personal information handling practices for both online and offline data and discloses what information we gather about you when you visit SpikeSource domains, use SpikeSource tools, or buy products and services directly from us. It describes how we use that information. 

## Information SpikeSource Gathers and Tracks

SpikeSource collects two kinds of information about users: 1) data that users volunteer by signing up to receive news and product information, subscribing to mailing lists or email delivery of our information systems, completing surveys, submitting information from our desktop tools or buying directly from us; and 2) aggregated tracking data we may collect when users interact with our Website or service interfaces. 

## Personal Information

We use the personal information you provide voluntarily to send information you have requested and to fulfill requests, for site and tool personalization and for statistical purposes. The specific use of your personal information varies, depending on how you contact us: 

  * When you subscribe to SpikeSource mailing lists to receive SpikeSource news and product information, you must provide an email address. We use that email address to send the requested information. We never sell or rent your email address that you provide when subscribing to our lists. 

  * When you post information to SpikeSource public mailing lists or message bases, this information will be visible to the public. SpikeSource mailing lists may be archived by third-party sites over which SpikeSource has no control, and your email address can be found from their archives. 

  * When you choose to share information with us, for example through our desktop tools or Website, we may report on that submission in anonymous statistical form, as well as use that information for site or content personalization. 

  * When you order SpikeSource products, subscribe to our services, or request information from us that depends upon your technology use, we record the technologies you're using in order to provide the service. Where that service may in part be provided through a partner, we will share your information with the partner in anonymous form. Our partner relationships provide equivalent privacy protection for such information as provided by this policy itself. We may also add you to our mailing lists and will contact you with SpikeSource-related issues now and then. 

  * We may from time to time offer certain programs with limited participation, for example closed beta programs. When you participate in such programs, we may require additional information to permit selection of participants. In addition, we will contact participants to collect program feedback periodically. These communications are not promotional in nature. 

  * Where we may use third parties in fulfilling some of our services, we share only the information necessary to fulfill the service, and our partner agreements provide equivalent privacy protection for such information as provided by this policy itself. 

We only release identifiable personal information when we believe that release is appropriate to comply with the law, or to protect the rights, property or safety of SpikeSource, our users or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. 

## Aggregated Tracking Information

We may analyze visitors' use of our sites and tools by tracking information such as downloads, page views, traffic flow, search terms and click-through. We use this information to improve our products and sites. We may also share or publish this anonymous traffic and demographic information in aggregate form. We do not share or publish any information that can identify an individual user. 

## Log Files

We use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information. 

## Cookies and Advertising

A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer's hard drive through your Web browser when you visit our sites. Cookies enable our systems to recognize your computer, so that we can provide you with personalized information and features. We may use cookies to help track user traffic patterns. This information is not linked to personally identifiable information. We use this anonymous data to improve our products and sites. 

We may use an outside advertising company to display advertisements on our site. These advertisements may contain cookies. While we use cookies in other parts of our Website, cookies received with banner or other ads are collected by these advertising companies, and we do not have access to or control over this information. 

You can set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies or to block cookies. If you block cookies, you may not be able to use certain site features or functions. 

## Data Retention

SpikeSource will not retain your personal information longer than is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected or as required by applicable laws or regulations. 

## Links

This site may contain links to other sites. SpikeSource is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of other Websites. 

## Surveys

We may run surveys on our site in which we ask our users for contact information (such as their email address). We may, with permission, use the contact information from the entry form to ask follow-up questions. Users may opt out of receiving future mailings. (See the choice and opt-out section below.) 

## Children’s Privacy

SpikeSource does not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. If we learn that we have collected personal information on a child under the age of 13, we will delete that data from our systems. SpikeSource encourages parents and guardians to go online with their children. Her are a few tips to help make a child’s online experience safer: (1) Teach children never to give personal information (such as name, address, phone number, school, etc.) unless supervised by a parent or responsible adult. (2) Know the sites your children are visiting and which sites are appropriate. (3) Look for website privacy policies and know how your child’s information is treated. 

## Security

This site has security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. All the data regarding users, their computers' system information and benchmark results are stored on a server. This server is located in a locked and guarded space, and only authorized SpikeSource personnel have access to the database containing given usernames and passwords. 

## Notification of Changes

If we change our Privacy Policy, we will post those changes on www.spikesource.com. If we decide to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, we will notify users by email. Users will be able to opt out of any new use of their personal information. 

## Choice and Opt-Out

Our site provides users the opportunity to opt out of receiving communications from us and from our partners at the point where we request information about the user. 

This site gives users the following options for removing their information from our database, so that they no longer receive future communications or access to our other services: 

  * You can unsubscribe from any of our mailing lists through your login profile at _<http://www.spikesource.com/sitemgr/site-login.php>_. 

  * You can unsubscribe from any email subscription to blogs, message bases, bug tracking systems and so forth through your access to that system. 

  * You can send email to info@spikesource.com info@spikesource.com stating your request. 

  * \You can reply to any unwanted communications that you receive, stating your request. 

## Contacting the Website

If you have any questions or comments about this privacy statement, the practices of this site or your dealings with this Website, you can contact _[webmaster@spikesource.com](mailto:webmaster@spikesource.com)_ and/or _[privacy@spikesource.com](mailto:privacy@spikesource.com)_. 

## Policy Updates

The SpikeSource Privacy Policy has been recently updated.  
Last Update: May 1, 2008
